Miller, J. Gormly Additional Papers /4170
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
J. Gormly Miller Additional Papers
1974-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, J. Gormly
/4170
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
3108947
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 24, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
J. Gormly Miller (1975-1979) - J. Gormly Miller received a Bachelor of Arts degree from University of Rochester in 1936 and a bachelor's degree in Library Service from Columbia University in 1938. He worked at the Rochester Public Library from 1938 to 1942, and served in the United States Army during World War II.
In 1946, Miller came to Cornell University as a librarian in the newly established School of Industrial and Labor Relations. From 1949 until his retirement in 1977, he served on the faculty of the ILR School as an associate professor and then a full professor, teaching courses in research methods. He held numerous consulting and special assignments, including advising the Department of Labor Relations at the University of Chile in Santiago on library development plans in 1961, and advising the U.S. Department of Labor on expanding library resources. From 1962 to 1970, he served as Assistant Director of personnel and budget for libraries. In 1970, he left for Geneva, Switzerland to become deputy chief of the Central Library and Documentation Branch of the United Nations' International Labor Agency.
Miller returned to Cornell in 1975 to assume the position of Director of the Cornell University Libraries. Under his administration, the library's total collection grew to more than four million volumes. Miller strengthened library rules and regulations to fight theft and vandalism. Space continued to be a problem, and the first off-site storage facility was built in 1979.
During Miller's stay at Cornell University, he actively participated in local government. He was an Ithaca alderman from 1959 to 1963 and again in 1968, when he was chairman of the Ithaca City Charter Revision Commission and co-chairman of the Common Council's Finance Committee. He retired from his post as University Librarian in 1979, but returned to serve as Acting Librarian in 1985.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4133: J. Gormly Miller Papers
Miller, J. Gormly.; Martin P. Catherwood Library
3108947
- ILR Faculty Bibliography First Revision (1 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ILR Faculty Bibliography First Revision (2 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ILR Faculty Bibliography First Revision (3 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ILR Faculty Bibliography First Revision (4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ILR 50th Anniversary Original Preliminary Draft (1/23/1995) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ILR 50th Anniversary Draft (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ILR 50th Anniversary Draft (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Irving M. Ives - An Upstate Progressive (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 50th Anniversary Book (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILR School 50th Anniversary - General (Box 2, Folder 1)
- McKersie Project - Goldberg, Elaine Greenfeld (Communications and Editorial Work) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Notes (Box 2, Folder 3)
- McKersie Project Notes - Meeting w/ McKersie, Goldberg and Supplements (5/23/1995) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- McKersie Project - Notes, Status Reports (May-June 1995) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- McKersie Project - Current Action, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- McKersie Project - Notes, Meeting with Lipsky - Elaine Goldberg (3/20/1995) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Notes and Reference Documents, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- McKersie Project - Messages and Correspondence (August-December 1994) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- McKersie Project - Timeline (Box 2, Folder 10)
- McKersie Project - Faculty Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fassimile Transmission of Faculty Bibliography and Timeline (7/28/1995) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- McKersie Project - McGinnis (Box 2, Folder 13)
- McKersie Project - Materials from R. McKersie for Sarvkis, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Professor Emeritus Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 15)
- LMS - Correspondence, McKersie Robert B. Project (Box 2, Folder 16)
- McKersie Project - Glycopantis (3/95), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Reference Documents (Box 2, Folder 18)
- McKersie Project - Reference Documents, Faculty Lists (Box 2, Folder 19)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Contributions Part 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Contributions Part 2 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Contributions Part 3 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- McKersie Project - Contributions, Frank Miller, History of Human Resource Studies Department (Box 2, Folder 23)
- McKersie Project - Preliminary Draft Complete (1/23/1995) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- McKersie Project - Preliminary Draft Supplementary Documents/Duplicates (Box 2, Folder 25)
- LMS-McKersie Project - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 26)
- ILR 50th Anniversary - Chapter 1-3, 8 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Information System Services - CISER (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Information Systems and Services - Dialogue Business Connection (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Information System and Services - HIRN (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Information System and Services - ILR Library (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Information Systems and Services - ISI (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Information Systems and Services - Labor Notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Information Systems and Services - Proquest (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Information Systems and Services - Human Resources Abstracts (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Information Systems and Services - LRP Publications (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Information Systems and Services - Software (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Information Systems and Services - Wilson Info. System (Box 3, Folder 11)
- LMS/WC Project - Reference Documents, Electronic Resources (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bibliographical Records (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Monographs (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Periodicals and Serial Films Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Periodicals and Serials - Employee Advocacy News (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Periodicals and Serials - Baywood Publ. Journal of Individual Employment (Box 3, Folder 17)
- LMS - Whitney-Carnegie Project (Box 3, Folder 18)
- ILR for Students (Box 3, Folder 19)
- LMS - Whitney-Carnegie Project - Academic Institutions References (Box 3, Folder 20)
- LMS/WC Project - References Documents, Stetson University College of Law (Box 3, Folder 21)
- LMS/WC Project - References, University Council of Industrial Relations (Box 3, Folder 22)
- LMS/WC Project - Government References (Box 3, Folder 23)
- LMS/WC Project - Survey of Organizations (Box 3, Folder 24)
- LMS/WC Project - Survey of Organizations, Letter 11/93, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- LMS/WC Project - Associations (Box 3, Folder 26)
- LMS/WC Project - Associations References (Box 3, Folder 27)
- LMS/WC Project - American Association for Affirmative Action (Box 3, Folder 28)
- LMS/WC Project - American Bar Association (Box 3, Folder 29)
- LMS/WC Project - American Compensation Association (Box 3, Folder 30)
- LMS/WC - American Compensation Association (Box 3, Folder 31)
- LMS/WC - American Industrial Hygiene Association (Box 3, Folder 32)
- LMS/WC Project - American Management Association (Box 3, Folder 33)
- LMS/WC Project - American Payroll Association (Box 3, Folder 34)
- LMS/WC Project - American Productivity and Quality Center (Box 3, Folder 35)
- LMS/WC Project - American Society for Training and Development (Box 3, Folder 36)
- LMS/WC Project - Association for Quality and Participation (Box 3, Folder 37)
- LMS/WC Project - Association for Union Democracy (Box 3, Folder 38)
- LMS/WC Project - Association of Human Resource Professionals (Box 3, Folder 39)
- LMS/WC Project - Association of Women Resource Systems Professionals (Box 3, Folder 40)
- LMS/WC Project - Association of Private Pension and Welfare Plans (Box 3, Folder 41)
- LMS/WC Project - CNYCOSH (Box 3, Folder 42)
- LMS/WC Project - Classification and Compensation Society (Box 3, Folder 43)
- LMS/WC Project - College and University Personnel Association (Box 3, Folder 44)
- LMS/WC Project - Associations Conference Board (Box 3, Folder 45)
- LMS/WC Project - Employee Assistance Professionals Associations (Box 3, Folder 46)
- LMS/WC Project - Employee Assistance Professionals Association (Box 3, Folder 47)
- LMS/WC Project - Employee Benefit Research Institute (Box 3, Folder 48)
- LMS/WC Project - Employers Council on Flexible Compensation (Box 3, Folder 49)
- LMS - Employment Management Association (Box 3, Folder 50)
- LMS/WC Project - Employment Policy Foundation (Box 3, Folder 51)
- LMS/WC Project - Human Factors and Economic Society (Box 3, Folder 52)
- LMS/WC Project - Human Resources Planning Society (Box 3, Folder 53)
- LMS/WC Project - Human Resources Research Organizations (Box 3, Folder 54)
- LMS/WC Project - Industrial Relations Counselors (Box 3, Folder 55)
- LMS/WC Project - Industrial Relations Research Association (Box 3, Folder 56)
- LMS/WC Project - Institute for Management (Box 3, Folder 57)
- LMS/WC Project - Institute of Industrial Engineers (Box 3, Folder 58)
- LMS/WC Project - Institute of Management Sciences (Box 4, Folder 1)
- LMS/WC Project - International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans (Box 4, Folder 2)
- LMS/WC Project - International Labor Communications Assoc. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- LMS/WC Project - International Labor Organization (Box 4, Folder 4)
- LMS/WC Project - International Personnel Management Association (Box 4, Folder 5)
- LMS/WC Project - Labor Institute of Public Affairs (Box 4, Folder 6)
- LMS/WC Project - Labor Policy Association (Box 4, Folder 7)
- LMS - Labor Research Association (Box 4, Folder 8)
- LMS/WC Project - Midwest Center for Labor Research (Box 4, Folder 9)
- LMS/WC Project - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 4, Folder 10)
- LMS/WC Project - National Association of Personnel Consultants (Box 4, Folder 11)
- LMS/WC Project - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 4, Folder 12)
- LMS/WC Project - National Center for Employee Ownership (Box 4, Folder 13)
- LMS/WC Project - National Center for the Workplace (Box 4, Folder 14)
- LMS/WC Project - National Committee on Pay Equity (Box 4, Folder 15)
- LMS/WC Project - National Council on Employment Policy (Box 4, Folder 16)
- LMS/WC Project - National Employee Services and Recreation Association (Box 4, Folder 17)
- LMS/WC Project - National Employment Counseling Association (Box 4, Folder 18)
- LMS/WC Project - National Lawyers Guild (Box 4, Folder 19)
- LMS/WC Project - National Research Bureau (Box 4, Folder 20)
- LMS/WC Project - Profit Sharing Council of America (Box 4, Folder 21)
- LMS/WC Project - Research Institute of America (Box 4, Folder 22)
- LMS/WC Project - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 4, Folder 23)
- LMS/WC Project - Human Resource Management (Box 4, Folder 24)
- LMS/WC Project - SPIDR (Box 4, Folder 25)
- LMS/WC Project - Urban Institute (Box 4, Folder 26)
- LMS/WC Project - W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment (Box 4, Folder 27)
- LMS/WC Project - Work in America Institute (Box 4, Folder 28)
- LMS/WC Project - Workers Compensation Research Institute (Box 4, Folder 29)
- LMS/WC Project - Miscellaneous Associations (Box 4, Folder 30)
- LMS/WC Project - Current Reference Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- LMS/WC Project - Computer Readable Database (Box 4, Folder 32)
- LMS/WC Project - Trial Formats, Professional Organizations (Box 4, Folder 33)
- JGM Working Folder - Reference Lists for Encyclopida of Business Information (Box 4, Folder 34)
- LMS/WC Project - Conferences (Box 4, Folder 35)
- LMS/WC Project - Publications (Box 4, Folder 36)
- WC Project Grant Application (Proposal) (Box 4, Folder 37)
- WC Project - SLA Grant Application (Proposal) (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project Outline (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Trial Formats Part 3 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Guide to Labor Law and Regulations (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - CIRL (Box 4, Folder 42)
- LMS/WC Project - General Correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Working Papers (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project (1991) (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Whitney-Carnegie Awards Proposal (Duplicate Copies) (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Whitney-Carnegie Awards Proposals (9/13/1990) (Box 4, Folder 47)
- LMS/WC Project - General (1990) (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Whitney-Carnegie Awards - March 1990 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Greenwood Publishing Group (Duplicate Documents) (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - General Publication Plans (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Publication Plans, BNA (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Publication Plans (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Lexis Guide 1-45 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Guide to Information Resources Outline (7/5/1993) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Guide to Information Resources Associate Database (2/23/1994) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Guide to Information Resources - "Series" List (6/6/1994) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Guide to Info Resources on Employment Relations in the US (8/12/1991) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Guide to Info Resources Book G-N (8/12/1991) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Guide to Info Resources Book O-Z (8/12/1991) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Pro-Cite Database: B1B1 (12/11/1990) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pro-Cite Database: B1B11 (3/21/1991) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- LMS Current Petition Pending (Box 5, Folder 10)
- LMS/WC Project - Academic Institutions, Misc. Notes (Box 5, Folder 11)
- LMS/WC Project - Associations, Misc. Notes (Box 5, Folder 12)
- LMS/WC Project - Conferences, Misc. Notes (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Notes and Files (Box 5, Folder 14)
- B1B100 (1991) (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Subject/Title Indexes (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - New Publications Development, Gale Research (Box 6, Folder 1)
- \Whitney-Carnegie Project - Haworth Press (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Publication Plans, ILR Press (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - LRP Publications (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Enclosures Submitted w/ Publishing Proposals (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - ILR Staff Planning Group, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Whitney-Carnegie Awards - Guide to Information Sources (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Guide to Information Sources (Box 6, Folder 8)
- LMS/WC Project - PROCITE (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Affirmative Action Requirements (Box 6, Folder 10)
- LMS/WC Project - Information Systems, BNA (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Comparison of Cornell Libraries with other Academic and Research Libraries (Parts 1-3), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Report of a Review of Staffing Levels Within the Cornell University Library System (Sept. 18, 1987) (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Report of a Review of Staffing Levels Within the Cornell University Library System (Sept. 18, 1987) (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Microcomputers in Libraries (Oct. 1980) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Microcomputers in Libraries (Oct. 1980) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Preliminary Review of Potential Microcomputer Use in Libraries, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- LMS/WC Project - Work Schedules, Training Plans (Box 6, Folder 18)
- LMS/WC Project - PBM Memos (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - General Bibliography (>1969) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- LMS/WC Project - Associations Reference Documents (Box 6, Folder 21)
- LMS/WC Project - Survey of Academic Institutes (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Databases (Box 6, Folder 23)
- LMS/WC Project - Government Agencies, Working Papers (Box 6, Folder 24)
- LMS/WC Project - Government Agencies, Reference Documents (Box 6, Folder 25)
- LMS/WC Project - Statistics, Working Papers (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Library Acquisitions (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Labor Law Letters and Regulations (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Cornell Jobs and Task Forces (Box 7, Folder 2)
- B1B43 - B1B52 Acquisitions, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- I.C. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- B1B23 - B1B27, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- B1B28 - B1B32, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- B1B33 - B1B37, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- B1B38 - B1B42, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- BIB-A and BIB-B (B1B100), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- BIB-C and BIB-D (B1B100), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- BIB-E (B1B100), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Guide to Information Resources - Gonvancy Database (Box 7, Folder 12)
- LMS/WC Project - Guide Introduction (Draft) (1993) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- LMS/WC Project - "Guide to " Outline (Box 7, Folder 14)
- LMS/WC Project - "Guide" Draft, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Part 1 General (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Part 1 General, Current Working Documents (Box 7, Folder 17)
- BNA Databases on the Lexis Service (Box 7, Folder 18)
- LMS/WC Project - Labor Law and Regulations, Reference Documents (Box 7, Folder 19)
- LMS/WC Project - Labor Law and Regulations, Working Papers (Box 7, Folder 20)
- LMS/WC Project - Notes on Labor Law and Regulation, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Guide to Information Resources - Series (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Current Working Folder (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Current Bibliographical Reference Documents (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Current Reference Documents (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Bibliographical Reference Documents (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - Bibliographical Style Guide, PBM Trial Formats (Box 7, Folder 27)
- LMS/WC Project - Appendices (Drafts) (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Whitney-Carnegie Project - "Guide to" Draft (3/17/93), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- JGM/File - CU, General (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Cornell Campaign Report Vol. 15, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Cornell Campaign Communique Vol. 16, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Cornell Campaign Communique Vol. 18, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Cornell Campaign Communique Vol. 19, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- JGM/Files - General/Libraries (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Cornell University Library - Development and Public Affairs (Box 8, Folder 7)
- CU General Libraries - Planning and Policy Board (Box 8, Folder 8)
- JGM/Files - General Technical Series (Box 8, Folder 9)
- University Library Archives (Box 8, Folder 10)
- ILR Library (Box 8, Folder 11)
- ILR - Catherwood Library Advisory Council, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Cornell ILR General (Box 8, Folder 13)
- ILR Library - John Goddard/Other Staff (Box 8, Folder 14)
- ILR Library - Planning Group (Box 8, Folder 15)
- ILR Library - Planning Project, 1993 References (Box 8, Folder 16)
- ILR Library - Shirley F. Harper (Box 8, Folder 17)
- ILO Library (Box 8, Folder 18)
- CUL - J.G. Miller - Personnel, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- JGM Files - Curriculum Vitz, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- ILO - United Nations - ACCIS (Box 8, Folder 21)
- JGM/Files - Law Library (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Tompkins County Public Library - CRP Project, "Books for You" (Box 8, Folder 23)
- J.G. Miller - Letters of Recommendation (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Statistics - CUL (Box 8, Folder 25)
- JGM - Personal, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- EDUCOM Consulting Group (Box 8, Folder 27)
- CU - Emeritus Professors' Tutorial Project, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- ILR - Alumni/School Relations (Box 8, Folder 29)
- JGM Files - S.A. McCarthy Memorial Room (Box 8, Folder 30)
- JGM Files - S.A. McCarthy Memorial Dedications, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- JGM - Cornell University Library Association, Stephen A. McCarthy Memorial Service, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- JGM Files - Stephen A. McCarthy (Box 9, Folder 3)
- JGM Files - University of Michigan, School Inform and Library Studies, Karen Markey (Box 9, Folder 4)
- CUL Director's File - CUL Annual Reports (Box 9, Folder 5)
- JGM/Files - Library Associates (Box 9, Folder 6)
- JGM/Files - Mann Library, Core Agricultural Literature Project (Box 9, Folder 7)
- JGM File - Academic Assembly (Box 9, Folder 8)
- JGM/File: CU Department of Rare Books (Box 9, Folder 9)
- JGM/Files: Industrial and Labor Relations Library (Box 9, Folder 10)
- JGM - Columbia University School of Library Services, Review, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Cornell University Libraries - Director's Files (Box 9, Folder 12)